Hello again and welcome to this new session about type A command decoding.
So decoding an ISO 14,443 type A command involves analyzing and interpreting the structure of the command
as it's transmitted between the reader, which we call also proximity coupling device or PCD, and the
card which we call also proximity integrated circuit card or Pic.
ISO 14,443 type A is the standard protocol used for near field communication, NFC and proximity cards.
So here is a breakdown through this presentation of how the decoding process works.
So what about the command structure.
So an ISO 14 443.
Type A command typically includes these elements.
So first of all we have SOV.
Start of frame which marks the beginning of the frame.
Then the second part is the command.
So the command or the instruction byte identifies the type of command.
For example request a wake up.
A select Anti-collision, etc. etc..
Then the third thing is the data field or payload.
So payload or data field carries additional data required for the command such as parameters or addresses.
Then which is a very important parameter in a command.
It's the CRC which is the cyclic redundancy check.
So CRC is composed by two bytes, which are used for error detection.
Crcs ensure data integrity and are crucial for verifying that the transmitted data has not been altered.
And finally, which is the fifth part of the command is the EOF, which is the end of frame.
So we have a start of frame and the end of frame.
The end of frame marks the end of the frame, which is very obvious regarding the command structure.
Then we have the Manchester encoding, the low level decoding.
So ISO 14,443 type A uses modified Miller encoding at 106 kilobit per second.
In this form of encoding, we have Uh, one bit, which is represented by a transition in the middle
of the bit period and a zero bit, which has no transition in the middle, but has transitions at the
beginning and end of each bit period.
So as you can see here, here's what corresponds to one bit.
And here what corresponds to the zero bit.
So as you can see here for the one we have a transition in the middle of the bit period.
Here is the middle.
So this is the middle of the bit period.
For the zero we have the transition not in the middle but at the beginning and end of each bit period.
So this bit level encoding allows the receiver to decode the signal even if it's received asynchronously.
Synchronously.
Then?
How is the decode of the frame?
So once the signal has been demodulated, the decoding process follows these steps.
First step is the frame synchronization synchronization, which identifies the soft start of frame and
EOF, and the frame to detect where each frame starts and ends.
Second step is the bit sampling, which converts the modulated waveform into bits according to the modified
Miller encoding rules.
Third step is the byte level assembly, which assemble bits into bytes, typically eight bits per byte,
starting from the SOV and ending at the EOF.
The fourth step is the CRC verification, which calculate and check the CRC to ensure the data integrity
of the frame.
And then the last step is the command interpretation.
It interprets the command byte to understand which action is being requested.
The reader interprets it according to the protocol specifications.
For example, request A for polling and select for card selection.
So as an example, let's work on the request a decoding rec a decoding.
So request A which is the request command.
Type A is used by the reader to detect cards in its field.
It's a short frame and typically one byte which is 26.
After decoding the waveform and identifying the request a command.
The ICC responds with an atca answer to request type A if it's in the field and active.
So let's walk through decoding a request A to see how the bits are interpreted in the ISO 14,443 type
A communication.
So here are the steps to decode request a.
The first step is receiving the frame.
The reader or the PCD sends out the request a command as a single byte.
Then we have the second step which is the modulated signal.
Modified Miller encoding.
So ISO 14,443 type A at 106kbps, uses modified Miller encoding, where one is represented by a transition
in the middle of the bit period, and zero is represented without transition in the middle, but a transition
at the beginning of the bit period.
So to send 26 we convert it to binary as you can see here.
So in binary it's 00100110.
The third step is the bit by bit analysis of the of the 26 bytes of the request a.
So the bit sequence from MSB to LSB is 0010 and then 0110.
So as we can see here we have the different transition of the request a.
So as we said we have the the representation is 00100110.
So as you can see here.
The first one is the the first presentation corresponds to zero.
Then we have another zero again.
Then from this point.
We go we do the transition.
And it represents a one bit.
It's sorry it's not clear.
But you can see here 001000110.
So as we have said before, the first part, which is a zero, we have the transition at the start.
No transition in the middle.
Then The second bit is a zero where the transition at the start, no transition in the middle.
Then we have the bit one where we have transition in the middle of the bit period.
Then we have a zero again because the transition is at the start, no transition in the middle.
And so on and so on and so on.
All the same with the same principle.
So then if we go back again we have the fifth step is interpreting the command.
After decoding the bits, the receiver assembles them back into the command byte according to ISO 14,443
26 correspond to the request a command used to poll for any cards in range.
So the fifth step is the response, which is the answer to request a atca.
So if a card is present in the field, it responds with an Atca, which includes the card type and other
information about its capabilities.
And here.
Here is a summary of the request a decoding.
I will let you have a look at it.
Then as an example we will talk about the anti-collision decoding.
So the anti-collision phase in ISO 14,443, type A involves sending a select command, which contains
a series of bytes including part of the card's Uuid, which is the unique identifier.
The encoding follows the modified Miller encoding rules.
To illustrate this, we will encode an example select command such as.
So command 9320.
So the first part is the 93 which select cascade level one and 93 is fixed for the first level of Anticollision.
Then we have the 20 byte which is the nvb the number of valid bits by indicating two complete bytes,
Uuid bits are sent in subsequent frames.
So how we encode these bytes.
So let's break it down and encode 9320 which is presented by the binary 100100110010 and 0000, which
uses the modified mirror encoding.
So regarding this picture about the modified Miller encoding, each bit is represented by a specific
signal level transition, as you have seen before.
So the bit one represents a transition which occurs in the middle of the bit period.
Regarding the bit zero, transition occurs at the start of the bit period, with no further transition
in the middle.